Logan Thomas

Senior Associate Data Scientist I **Protection Engineering Consultants** Austin, TX



About me

I'm a highly motivated and naturally curious individual with 6 years of experience using data science & machine learning techniques.

I exhibit an analytical and detailoriented nature while placing strong value on building relationships.

Skills



Awards

Essentials Program Selection Nielsen | 2019

Data Science Collaby Award Nielsen | 2017

Simply Excellent Platinum Award Nielsen | 2017

Outstanding Graduate for Mathematics Palm Beach Atlantic University | 2012

Outstanding Leadership Award Palm Beach Atlantic University | 2011

Don Harp Athletics Leadership Award Palm Beach Atlantic University | 2011

Contact



✓ logan.thomas005@gmail.com

(321) 961-9107

in logan-thomas

loganthomas

Experience

Senior Associate Data Scientist I

Protection Engineering Consultants: Austin, TX | Aug 2019 - Present Advanced Technology & Research Team

- Developed evolutionary algorithm library for deploying multi-gene genetic programming and symbolic regression
- Enhanced computer vision algorithms for autonomous fragment tracking
- · Python technical lead and Git evangelist
- · Security Clearance as of Sept 2020

Python Technical Curriculum Developer & Online Instructor

DataCamp: Remote | Feb 2019 - Present

- Designed, created, and currently maintain "Writing Efficient Python Code"
- 20k+ students, 4.5/5 average course rating

Lead Data Scientist

Nielsen: Austin, TX | Oct 2018 - Aug 2019 Machine Learning & Algorithms Team

- Researched and implemented machine learning models
- Discovered relationships and detected anomalies in large datasets
- Synthesized disparate datasets to influence decision making
- Advocate for clean code, version control, and unit testing

Senior Data Scientist

Nielsen: San Francisco, CA | Aug 2016 - Oct 2018 Digital Product Team

- Engineered automated natural language processing engine utilizing network analysis, graph theory, and TF-IDF methods
- Deployed autonomous training pipeline for LSTM deep learning model using Databricks, AWS, TensorFlow, and Keras
- Created optimization routine leveraging random forests, k-dimensional trees, and CVXPY

Applied Analytics Program Associate - School of Professional Studies

Columbia University: Remote | Sep 2016 - Dec 2016 Applied Analytics in an Organizational Context

Data Scientist

Nielsen: Tampa, FL & San Francisco, CA | July 2014 - Aug 2016 Emerging Leaders Program

Education

University of Florida | 2012 - 2014

Master of Science in Mechanical Engineering Minor in Statistics

Palm Beach Atlantic University | 2008 - 2012

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics Minor in Biblical Studies; Graduated Summa Cum Laude

<> Contributions

Open Source:

₽ pyjanitor ₽ deap ₽ pint

Personal:

turkey-bowl P python-practice ₽ repo-scrape